Guide to the Departmental and Academic Program Annual Reports, 1874 - 2007
Departmental and Academic Program Annual Reports 1874 - 2007
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University
1000-15
15
35
Annual reports of academic departments, programs and academic divisions of the university.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Collected by the Provost and later the Vice President of Academic Affairs.
Collection Overview
Annual reports of academic departments and interdisciplinary academic programs of Wesleyan University and other academic divisions of the university that are supervised by the Office of Academic Affairs (e.g. the libraries or the Wesleyan University Press). Included in reports are annual discussions of curriculum, class size, staffing, faculty activities, department-sponsored events, milestones, and long-range planning concerns.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by department or program and then chronologically.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Administration
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Departments
Universities and colleges--Administration
Universities and colleges--Departments
Related Material
See also the University Archives Vertical File collection for documents concerning specific departments or individuals, and the collection of faculty meeting minutes. The Wesleyan University Bulletin (1888-1961) contains reports of departmental activities and individual accomplishments. The Annual Report of the President, the Treasurer, and the University Annual Report are also available for most years.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Departmental and academic annual reports, 1874-2007, 35 boxes, 15 linear feet
  - Administration: Alumni Council, 1956-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Admissions, 1971-1972, 1976-1980, 1982-1984, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3-5)
  - Administrative President's Reports, 1962-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - African Studies Program, 1976-1977, 1980-1982, 1983-1984, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - African-American Studies, 1971-1973, 1976-1988, 1989-1998, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - American Studies Program, 1960-1961, 1967-1968, 1969-1985, 1986-1990, 1991-2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Anthropology, 1967-1973, 1974-2001 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Art, 1956-1997 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
    See also Art and Art History.
  - Art and Art History, 1997-2001 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Asian Languages and Literatures, 1961-1962, 1967-1969, 1975-1990, 1991-2001 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Astronomy, 1956-2001 (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
  - Biology, 1898-1899, 1903-1904, 1908-1910, 1917-1920, 1922-1947, 1956-1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Biology, 1963-1990, 1991-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
  - Campus Buildings, 1956-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Career Planning Center, 1963-1964, 1966-1976, 1977-1984, 1985-1993, 1994-1996, 1998-1999 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Center for Advanced Studies, 1956-1962, 1963-1965, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Center for the Americas, 1997-2001 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Center for the Arts, 1965-1966, 1970-1971, 1974-1981 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Center for the Arts, 1981-1989, 1990-2003 (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
  - Center for the Arts, 2003-2007 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Center for the Humanities, 1962-1965, 1969-1988 (Box 8, Folder 3-7)
  - Center for the Humanities, 1988-2001 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Chemistry, 1874-1875, 1886-1887, 1891-1892, 1893-1894, 1898-1899, 1900-1901, 1902-1904, 1908-1910, 1921-1922, 1956-1959, 1960-1962, 1963-2001 (Box 9, Folder 4-6)
  - Classics, 1874-1876, 1898-1899, 1900-1901, 1902-1904, 1908-1910, 1931-1932, 1934-1935, 1936-1937, 1938-1949 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Classics, 1949-2001 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - College of Letters, 1959-1979 (Box 10, Folder 4-7)
  - College of Letters, 1979-1989, 1990-2001 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - College of Quantitative Studies, 1960-1967 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - College of Social Studies, 1959-2001 (Box 11, Folder 5-7)
  - Computer Lab, 1962-1965, 1967-1972, 1973-1982 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Dance, 1986-1996, 1997-2001 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Davison Art Center, 1954-1955, 1967-2001 (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
  - Dean's Reports, 1957-1958, 1972-1983 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Development, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Earth and Environmental Sciences, 1973-1981 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Earth and Environmental Sciences, 1981-2001 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
  - East Asian Studies Program, 1973-1974, 1975-2001 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Economics, 1903-1904, 1908-1910, 1956-1987 (Box 13, Folder 5-7)
  - Economics, 1987-2001 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Educational Policy Committee, 1956-1957, 1959-1965, 1966-1974, 1975-1992, 1994-1995, 1996-2001 (Box 14, Folder 3-6)
  - Educational Studies Program, 1957-1967, 1968-1985, 1986-1987, 1988-1991 (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
  - English, 1874-1875, 1898-1899, 1902-1904, 1905-1906, 1942-1991 (Box 15, Folder 5-8)
  - English, 1991-2001 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - English Language and English Literature, 1893-1894, 1898-1899, 1908-1910 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - English (Writing Workshop), 1982-1992, 1993-1994, 1995-2001 (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
  - Faculty Student Affairs Committee, 1998-2000 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Film Studies Program, 1996-2001 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Geology, 1893-1894, 1898-1899, 1903-1904, 1908-1910, 1956-1973 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - German, 1906-1907, 1916-1937, 1938-1951, 1952-1955, 1956-1966, 1967-2001 (Box 17, Folder 1-7)
  - German, 1908-1910, 1911-1912, 1914-1916, 1917-1918 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - General Humanities, 1956-1963, 1956-1969, 1970-1975, 1976-1977, 1978-1982, 1983-1984, 1985-1989 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
  - General Sciences, 1958-1966, 1967-1977, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
  - Government, 1944-1945, 1946-1949, 1951-1953, 1954-1963, 1964-1965, 1966-1991 (Box 18, Folder 6-9)
  - Government, 1991-2001 (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
  - Graduate School, 1956, 1959, 1961-1971, 1972-1976, 1981-1983 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
    Includes Program in Teacher Preparation proposal.
  - Health Education, 1987-1989, 1994-1995, 1997-1998 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Health Services, 1956-1978, 1979-1986, 1987-1990 (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
  - History, 1903-1904, 1908-1910, 1956-2001 (Box 20, Folder 3-7)
  - History and Theory, 1970-1971, 1975-1977, 1978-1980, 1981-1990 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - History and Theory, 1991-2001 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Honors College/Russell House, 1956-1990, 1991-1993, 1994-1998, 1999-2000 (Box 21, Folder 2-5)
  - Institutional Research/Career Planning, 1971-1981 (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
  - International Studies, 1994-2001 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Includes major creation proposal.
  - Jewish Studies, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Language Laboratory, 1981-1983, 1985-1990, 1991-1992, 1993-1996, 1998-1999 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Latin American Studies, 1970-1973, 1974-1988, 1989-1995, 1997-2001 (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
  - Linguistics Program, 1967-1985, 1986-1988 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Literature, Freshman Program in, 1964-1981 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Mathematics, 1898-1899, 1956-1987, 1988-1989, 1990-1991 (Box 22, Folder 8-11)
  - Mathematics and Astronomy; Mathematics, 1875-1876, 1908-1910 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Mathematics/Mathematics and Computer Science, 1991-2001 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Medieval Studies, 1988-1995, 1996-1997, 1998-1999, 2000-2002 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Ministry and Havurah, 1956-1957, 1964-1965, 1966-1990 (Box 23, Folder 5-7)
    At the front of folder 5 are six undated reports.
  - Molecular Biology and Biochemistry, 1984-1987, 1989-1997 (Box 23, Folder 8-9)
  - Molecular Biology and Biochemistry, 1997-2001 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Museum, 1936-1940 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Music, 1956-1974, 1975-1988 (Box 24, Folder 3-8)
  - Music, 1988-2001 (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
  - Neuroscience and Behavior Program, 1990-2001 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Olin Library, 1956-1964, 1965-1985 (Box 25, Folder 5-8)
  - Olin Library, 1985-1993, 1994-2001 (Box 26, Folder 1-5)
  - Oral English Program, 1962-1966, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy, 1893-1894, 1989-1899, 1903-1904, 1908-1910, 1956-1990 (Box 26, Folder 7-9)
  - Philosophy, 1990-2001 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Physical Education, 1956-1959, 1960-1993 (Box 27, Folder 2-7)
  - Physical Education, 1993-2001 (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
  - Physics, 1893-1894, 1898-1899, 1903-1904, 1908-1910, 1956-1989 (Box 28, Folder 4-6)
  - Physics, 1990-2001 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Psychology, 1956-2001 (Box 29, Folder 2-6)
  - Public Affairs Center, 1953-1955, 1956-1963, 1964-1965, 1967-1971, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Religion, 1956-1960, 1961-1977 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    At the front of the folder are five undated reports.
  - Religion, 1977-2001 (Box 30, Folder 1-4)
  - Romance Languages, 1893-1894, 1898-1899, 1908-1910, 1956-1986 (Box 30, Folder 5-8)
  - Romance Languages, 1986-2001 (Box 31, Folder 1-5)
  - Romance Languages, 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    The report is for the program in Paris.
  - Russian, 1956-1960, 1961-2001 (Box 32, Folder 1-3)
  - Science in Society Program, 1975-2001 (Box 32, Folder 4-6)
  - Sociology, 1967-2001 (Box 32, Folder 7-9)
  - Speech and Speech Communication Program, 1973-1976 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Theater/Dance, 1956-1962, 1963-1966, 1967-1970, 1971-1988 (Box 33, Folder 2-4)
  - Theater, 1991-2001 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Wesleyan University Press, 1956-1961, 1962-1980, 1981-1982 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
  - Wesleyan University Press, 1999-2001 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Western Civilization Program, 1956-1960, 1961-1967 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Women's Studies, 1980-2001 (Box 34, Folder 3-6)
- Oversize
  - English Language and English Literature, 1893-1894, 1898-1899, 1908-1910 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - German, 1908-1910, 1911-1912, 1914-1916, 1917-1918 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Mathematics and Astronomy; Mathematics, 1875-1876, 1908-1910 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Romance Languages, 1987-1988 (Box 35, Folder 4)